本:如果迈克还不出来的话,我可以吃他的馄饨吗?
Ben: If Mike doesn't show up, can I have his ravioli?
所有人:不行.
Everyone: No.
麦琪:迈克到底去哪了?他通常会在吃饭的时候回家的.
Maggie: Where is Mike anyway?He's usually home from work by dinner time.
本:可能洗车的地方出了一些意外.
Ben: They could have had an emergency at the carwash.
开萝尔:意外.高速公路上有暴风雪?
Carol: An emergency.What a bug storm on the expressway?
杰森:开萝尔,迈克找了份工作,
Jason: Carol, there's nothing wrong with having a part time job that involves
体力活,这不是件坏事,他需要赚钱来付房租.
a little physical labor.The money helps Mike pay his way around here.
开萝尔:我也可以找份工作吗?
Carol: So I could get a part time job too?
杰森:付你的房租?
Jason: To pay your way around here?
开萝尔:对,付我在这的房租.
Carol: Heck no.I mean of course to help pay my way around here.
杰森:我不好说,你觉得呢,麦琪?
Jason: I don't know.What do you think Maggie?
麦琪:可以,只要你别去跳脱衣舞.
Maggie: Fine.As long as you don't become a topless dancer.
开萝尔:哦,太好了.我明天就去马路上留心.
Carol: Oh great.I'll start pouting the pavement tomorrow.
本:看外面.
Ben: Look out pavement.
迈克:嘿,对不起你们,我回来晚了.
Mike: Hey.Sorry I'm late guys.Emergency overtime.Bug storm on the expressway.
出了些紧急情况,耽误了,
You know, you know I hate my job,
高速公路上有暴风雪.唉,我讨厌我的工作,
if I could find anything else I'd jump at it.
我应该找一个我感兴趣的工作.该死的洗汽车,
The only good thing about this stupid carwash job is payday.
唯一开心的时候就是发工资的日子.今天是星期六,我准备去参加个聚会.
Boy its Saturday and I am ready to party.
杰森:发工资的日子!那么你也准备好付这个月的房租了.
Jason: Payday!Well then you're also ready to pay this months rent.
迈克:是的,没问题.
Mike: Yeah, no problem.
杰森:还有上个月的.
Jason: And last month's rent.
迈克:哦,没问题.
Mike: Uh, no problem.
开萝尔:你还能把欠我的20块钱还我吗?
Carol: So you can also pay me back the twenty dollars you borrowed?
迈克:不行.
Mike: No.
开萝尔:没问题.
Carol: No problem.
迈克:嘿,好的,现在我还能指望这两块钱干什么呢?
Mike: Hey.Alright, now what the heck am I supposed to do with two dollars?
本:你可以和我一起玩电子游戏.
Ben: You could come play some video games with me.
迈克:本,一个大学生在星期六的晚上有很多更重要的事要做,
Mike: Bennie, a college man has much more important things to do on a
怎么能和他的小弟弟玩什么这种无聊的游戏呢?
Saturday night than destroying galaxies with his dweebie little brother.
本:我买单.
Ben: I'll buy.
迈克:那我们走吧.
Mike: Let's roll.
本:喔,你刚才成了疯狂的银河杀手!
Ben: Wow.You just mad intergalactic assassin!
迈克:我简直太开心了.
Mike: Words cannot express my joy.
本:还要一块玉米煎饼吗?
Ben: Want another burrito?
迈克:不,我还在吃呢.
Mike: No.I'm still tasting that last one.
你知道,
You know Bennie, there's got to be more to life than working in a stupid
本,生活要比重复地洗汽车和吃煎饼丰富的多.
car wash and eating burritos that repeat.
本:那么换个工作吧.
Ben: So get another job.
迈克:我一直在找一份新的工作,三个星期了,
Mike: I've been looking for a new job for the passed three weeks.
你知道,一份工作可不容易找.
You know a job is not easy to find.
本:的确是这样.对不起,你这需要帮忙吗?
Ben: Sure it is.Excuse me; do you need any help here?
男人:是的,我可以帮忙.
Man: Yes, I can help.
本:不,不.我们想找份工作,应该找谁呢?
Ben: No no.Who do we see to get this gopher a job?
男人:工作?
Man: Job?
本:是的,我们找份工作要找谁呢?
Ben: Yeah, who do we see for a job?
男人:工作?啊,
Man: Job?Ah sorry, don't carry pork chop,
很抱歉,不用带猪排,我们有猪肉香肠和猪肉皮.
but we've got pork sausage and pork rind.
迈克:不,不,本,本,别管了.
Mike: No, no.Bennie, Bennie, never mind.
本:你需要其他人在这工作吗?
Ben: Do you need other people to work here?
男人:在这工作.是的,我就在这工作.
Man: Work here, yes.I work here.
迈克:不用了,本,算了.
Mike: No Bennie, forget it.
本:在这工作,他.
Ben: Work here.Him.
男人:啊,我给你个小坛子.
Man: Ah, I get for you mini jar.
迈克:小坛子?
Mike: Mini jar?
本:经理,真是太好了.
Ben: The manager.That would be great.
迈克:我,我,很好.
Mike: I, I, that would be good.
本:当经理来这后,我去和他谈.
Ben: When the mini jar gets here, let me do all the talking.
迈克:我谈我自己,好的.
Mike: I'll do my own talking, alright.
经理:啊,你们两个谁找工作?
Manager: Ah, well which one of you men is looking for work?
本:他.我来给你介绍他的情况.
Ben: He is.Let me tell you about the lad.
经理:我是尼克西蒙,你是?
Manager: I'm Nick Simpson, and you're?
本:迈克?西维尔.
Ben: Mike Seaver.
迈克:迈克?西维尔.
Mike: Mike Seaver.
经理:哦,他是你的经纪人,对吗?
Manager: Oh, and this is your agent, right?
迈克:是的.
Mike: Right.
本:啊,什么是经纪人?
Ben: Ah, what's an agent?
经理:给你找工作,然后得到提成的人.
Manager: Somebody who gets you a job and then gets a piece of the action.
本:我是他的经纪人,本?西维尔,很高兴见到你.
Ben: I'm his agent.Ben Seaver.Pleased to meet you.
经理:你好,本.迈克,你看起来是一个好小伙.
Manager: Hello Ben.You look like a nice kid Mike.
迈克:是的,我是.
Mike: Well, I am.
本:他是.
Ben: He am.
经理:你以前在哪工作?
Manager: Have you ever worked before?
迈克:哦,我有过两份工作.
Mike: Yeah.I've had two other jobs.
经理:你是一位学生吧?
Manager: Are you a full time student?
迈克:是的,我是拉尔夫?兰登初级学院的.
Mike: Yeah.I go to Alf Landen Junior college.
经理:你怎么过来呢?
Manager: Do you have a way to get here?
迈克:我有车,就在外面.
Mike: Yeah.My car's right outside.
经理:很好,听着,
Manager: Well listen, the late shift starts in fifteen minutes.
一刻钟以后你就来上夜班吧.你愿意吗?
Are you interested?
本:我们愿意.
Ben: We'll take it.
迈克:我们愿意.好的,你想让我马上开始?
Mike: We'll take it.Yeah.You mean you want me to start right now?
经理:是的,我马上就要人.
Manager: Oh yes.I need a man right away.Poor Raji is working a double shift.
可怜的拉吉一个人做两班,他工作得太辛苦了,他的眼珠都快要掉下来了.
He's been working so hard, his dot is about to fall off.
杰森:嘿,你好,本.
Jason: Hey hi Ben.
本:好,好,好.别想让我振作起来.
Ben: Yeah, yeah, yeah.Don't try and cheer me up.
杰森:怎么了?
Jason: About what?
本:我给他找了一份新工作,他却让我步行回家.
Ben: he makes me walk home after I find him a new job.
麦琪:谁?
Maggie: Who?
本:我.
Ben: Me.
麦琪:不,谁找了一份新工作?
Maggie: No.Who got a new job?
本:迈克.一刻钟之前,没有我的话他会一直洗汽车的.
Ben: Mike.He started fifteen minutes ago.Let's see how long he lasts without me.
开萝尔:你给迈克找了一份工作.
Carol: You got Mike a job?
本:是的.你还没听见吗?
Ben: Yeah.Haven't you been listening?
杰森:我承认,本,我没有在听你.过来,重新说吧.
Jason: I confess Ben.I haven't been listening either.Come on, start over.
本:好,好,好.别想让我振作起来.
Ben: Yeah, yeah, yeah.Don't try and cheer me up.
杰森:开头太长了,简短一点吧.
Jason: Enough about the jokes.Give me a little exposition here.
本:好的,迈克在一家叫做"停与行"的百货店里上夜班.
Ben: Ok.Mike's working the graveyard shift at the Stop and Run.
麦琪:什么班?
Maggie: The what shift?
本:夜班.
Ben: The graveyard shift.
麦琪:我可不喜欢.
Maggie: I don't think I like that.
本:你们不喜欢!你们不用步行回家.
Ben: You don't like it!You didn't have to walk home.
麦琪:不,不.
Maggie: No, no.A lot of robberies happen at those stores,
这些商店经常发生抢劫,大多数都发生在夜里.
and most of them happen late at night.
本:没事,柜台下面有把枪.能发生什么呢?
Ben: Relax.He's got a gun under the counter.What could happen?
拉吉:记得把所有钱锁起来,要不然他们真的会杀了你.
Raj: And remember all cash in overnight machine, or they kill you for sure.
迈克:好的,我会记住的.
Mike: Alright, I'll remember that.
拉吉:好.这些是霍霍的,于胡的,叮咚的.
Raj: OK.These are Ho Ho's, Yu Who's, Ding Dongs.
迈克:喔.
Mike: Wow.
拉吉:不用拿喔喔的,没人买.
Raj: No longer carry Wow Wow's.Nobody buy.
(电话铃声)
(Phone rings)
拉吉:不,这是我的电话.
Raj: No.It was for me.From girlfriend Hiya.
我的女朋友哈雅,她说她很想我.
She is calling to say I'm being on her mind.
迈克:啊,她真可爱.
Mike: Ah, that is kinda cute.
拉吉:明晚不用打电话了,今天是我最后一次夜班,
Raj: Tomorrow night, not having to call.
谢谢你.明晚就可以……
This last night on graveyard, thanks be to you.Tomorrow night it will be...
迈克:有人来了?
Mike: You Who Dong Dong?
拉吉:啊,我给你示范一下怎样对付顾客.看仔细点.
Raj: Ah, I show you how to handle customer.Watch closely.
迈克:好的.
Mike: OK.
拉吉:我可以帮你吗?啊,你好.
Raj: May I help you please?So much.Ahh, Nameste.
顾客:你好.
Customer: Nameste.
(他们说着北印度语)
(They speak in Hindi)
顾客:不是喔喔!好吧.
Customer: No Wow Wow!Ok.
拉吉:有问题吗?
Raj: Any questions?
迈克:妈妈.
Mike: Mum.
麦琪:哦,你好,迈克.
Maggie: Oh, Hi Mike.
迈克:你半夜里在擦银制品?
Mike: You're polishing the silver ware in the middle of the night?
麦琪:这得经常擦,可我没有时间,没有时间.
Maggie: Well it had to be done some time and I've been putting it off and putting it off.
迈克:妈妈,妈妈.你在担心什么?
Mike: Mum, mum.What are you worried about?
麦琪:没事,没事.当然不是你.你们在柜台下面有一把枪.
Maggie: Nothing, nothing.Certainly not you.You've got a gun under the counter and everything.
迈克:哦,你听说我的新工作了?
Mike: Oh, you heard about my new job?
麦琪:是的.
Maggie: I did.
迈克:听着,不用担心.我是说,今晚我就见了几个失眠的人,买了一些冷煎饼.你要一个吗?好了,我要去睡了.
Mike: Well listen, there's nothing to worried about.I mean all I saw tonight was a bunch of insomniacs buying frozen burritos.You want one?Right, I'll turn in.
麦琪:迈克,你爸爸和我同意不再像对一个小孩子那样强迫你干什么了,
Maggie: Mike, your father and I agreed that we can't order you around
如果这是你想要的工作,那就随你吧.
like a kid anymore.If this is a job you want, so be it.
迈克:那是非常成熟的态度,妈妈.
Mike: It's a very mature attitude mum.
麦琪:我是勉强同意的.
Maggie: It was a very close vote.
迈克:我很感激,晚安.
Mike: And I appreciate it.Goodnight.
麦琪:你能简单地咨询一下是否能调换一下工作安排吗?
Maggie: I suppose it would be too much to ask you to simply enquire about
这样可以让你可怜的妈妈不用担心早死.不说了,
a schedule change?Just to keep your poor mother form worrying herself
晚安.
into an early grave.So don't.Goodnight.
迈克:好了,妈妈.看,
Mike: Alright mum.Look, I'm the new guy in town.
我是个新人,我不可能一进去,就对工作时间提出要求.
I can't just go in there and start demanding these primo hours.
麦琪:听我说,如果让你提这样一个要求有些过分,我理解.哦,
Maggie: Like I said, if it's too much to ask you to merely make the request,
睡吧,宝贝.我很好,真的很好.
I understand.Oh sleep well honey.I'll be fine.Really.
迈克:妈妈.好的,
Mike: Mum look.Alright, I'll ask my boss.
我对我的老板提,但是我知道他的答案会是什么.
But I know what his answers going to be.
麦琪:亲爱的,他的答案是?
Maggie: His answer to what dear?
迈克:让我离开这见鬼的夜班.
Mike: To me getting off the stupid graveyard shift.
麦琪:哦,如果那样的话,你应该提.
Maggie: Oh if that's what you think you should do.
迈克:好的.
Mike: Right.
麦琪:呵呵.我真替自己感到难为情,这孩子上了我的当.
Maggie: He he he.I should be ashamed of myself.The kid didn't stand a chance.
迈克:你好,拉吉.
Mike: Yo, Raj.
拉吉:你好,肉排.你怎么样?
Raj: Yo pork chop.How are you doing?
迈克:哦,很高兴见到你在这儿,不过真不愿意看到你还在工作.
Mike: Oh, very well to be seeing you here.But not so pleased to be seeing you at work.
拉吉:哈,我可是两班.
Raj: Ha.I am double shifting.
经理:拉吉,你已经在这工作很久了,
Manager: Raj.You've been working here too long.
我实际上开始理解你了.
I'm actually beginning to understand you.Aren't you a shade early?
你是不是太早了,早了12个小时.
Like about twelve hours.
迈克:听着,这正是我想找你商量的.
Mike: Yeah, listen.That's kind of what I want to ask you about.
经理:等一下.杰瑞,很高兴你在这儿.
Manager: Hang on a second.Jerry, I'm glad you're here.Grab an apron please.
请拿一个围裙,拉吉要下班了.哦,杰瑞,
Raj is about to drop.Oh and Jerry, this is Mike Seaver here.
这是迈克?西维尔,他将负责夜班.
He'll be taking over graveyard.
杰瑞:哦,真的?
Jerry: Oh really?
迈克:你好,是真的.
Mike: Hi yeah.
经理:不要吓唬他,
Manager: And don't scare him about working graveyard with your silly little
别对他提你上夜班时遇到了强盗的事.
robber story.
杰瑞:来,我不会那样做,至少他的第一个星期不会.
Jerry: Come on.I wouldn't do that.Not on his first week.
迈克:什么强盗的事?
Mike: What silly little robbery story?
经理:哦,没有的事.你在想什么呢?
Manager: Oh forget it.So what's on your mind?
迈克:听着,尼克,
Mike: Listen Nick, I know that I am new here,
我知道我是这儿的新人,
so I don't even expect you to consider this,
因此我不能指望你考虑这些,但是我告诉我妈妈我至少得向你提出一下请求.
but I told my mum that I would at least ask and make the request.
经理:不,不,不,
Manager: No, no, no.I cannot make you the manager.Not in the first week.
我不可能让你成为经理,至少第一个星期不可以.开个玩笑.
Only kidding.
迈克:好的,我换一个更安全的班,
Mike: Right.Well, see,
这样我就可以坦诚地告诉我妈,就这样,我提了,
I want to be able to honestly tell my mother that I asked to be put
你听了,谢谢.
on a safer shift.So there.I asked.You listened.Thanks.
经理:白班会对你更好些,你妈妈很明智.
Manager: So the day shift would be better for you, mum wise.
你想说的是这意思吗?
Is that what you are trying to say?
迈克:是的,但是……
Mike: Well yeah, but...
经理:坚持住,我知道怎么做.
Manager: Hang on.I'll see what I can do.Jerry!
杰瑞!听着,你不介意做晚班吧?
Listen, you didn't mind working the late shift did you?
杰瑞:是的,我很习惯.
Jerry: No.I got used to it.
经理:你可以继续习惯,好吗?
Manager: Well you can get used to it again, right?
杰瑞:好的,好的,我想是这样.
Jerry: Yeah, yeah.I guess so.
经理:好的,你和拉吉轮流做夜班吧.
Manager: Good.So you and Raj will be splitting grave yard.
你没问题了,拉吉在这儿吧?
No problem there with you, is there Raj?
拉吉:我……可以,我在这儿,尼克.
Raj: Well I...sure.I be here Nick.
迈克:哦,尼克.
Mike: Uh, look Nick.I feel kind of funny here.
我这样是不是很好笑,我刚来这儿,我认为这可能不公平……
I just started here and I don't think it's fair that...
经理:不,不,你完全正确.我让你做夜班,也不公平,开个玩笑.
Manager: Yes, yes.You are absolutely right.I'm going to put you back on graveyard.It wouldn't be fair.I'm only kidding.
迈克:好的,好的.
Mike: Right right.It's just that I know how much it mean to Raj and, and,
我知道这样对拉吉意味着什么,
it's just that they've been here longer and I don't think it's fair that
他们已经来这很久了,让他们做夜班可能不公平.
they should get stuck with the graveyard..
经理:迈克.如果我们不关心自己,谁来关心呢?
Manager: Mike, please.If we can't take care of our own, who will?
杰森:嘿,你好,迈克.你在家里也穿着这样的蓝制服四处游荡?
Jason: Hey, Hi Mike.Do you realize that you are wondering around aimlessly in a puke blue jacket?
迈克:哦,我,我十分钟后就要去上班了.
Mike: Oh, I, I got to go to work in ten minutes.
麦琪:哦,你换了班了?
Maggie: Oh, you got the shift change?
迈克:是的,是真的.
Mike: Yeah.Sure did.
麦琪:哦,现在你应该很高兴了.
Maggie: Oh now aren't you glad you asked?
迈克:快乐无法言喻.
Mike: Words cannot express my joy.
杰森:迈克.
Jason: Mike.
迈克:嘿,爸爸,
Mike: Hey dad, let me ask you something.
让我问你件事.你有没有得到过某些真得很好,却不配拥有的东西.
Have you even got something really good, that you didn't deserve?
麦琪:哦,他有.他得到了我.
Maggie: Oh, sure he did.He got me.
迈克:不,不,不.我是说你很想得到的东西.
Mike: No, no, no.I mean something that you really wanted.
麦琪:继续说,迈克.
Maggie: Go on Mike.
杰森:快点.
Jason: Quickly.
迈克:好的,爸爸.我是说有人对你很好,是因为你的身份,而不是你做了些什么或者你做得怎么样?
Mike: Well dad, I mean has someone ever treated you really nice, because of who you are, and not what you did or how well you did it?
杰森:迈克,迈克,
Jason: Mike, Mike, Mike.Does this involve a girl?
迈克.这和女孩有关吗?很抱歉.
I'm sorry, I'm just trying to make sense out of something the boys trying
看他的样子,我以为会和姑娘有关系.
to share with us.
迈克:我要走了.
Mike: Look, I got to go.
麦琪:迈克,你别生气.
Maggie: Mike, you're not making any sense.
杰森:你生气了?
Jason: Are you upset?
迈克:嘿,我怎么会生气?
Mike: Hey, how could I be upset?
我只是有了一份新工作,那里很暖和,
I just got a new job, where I'm kept warm,
工作安全,还能穿一件蓝制服.
I work safe hours and I wear a puke blue jacket.
麦琪:女孩!
Maggie: A girl!
杰森:哦,难道你没想到吗?
Jason: Oh so you weren't thinking that?
迈克:你好,拉吉.你怎么样?
Mike: Yo Raj.How are you doing?
拉吉:迈克,我现在很忙.
Raj: Mike.I'm kind of busy right now.
迈克:好的,拉吉,我真的想说声对不起,因为……
Mike: Yeah well listen.Raj.I really want to apologize for...
拉吉:忙,忙,很忙.
Raj: Busy.Busy, busy.
迈克:嘿,杰瑞,你怎么样?
Mike: Hey jerry man.How's it going?
杰瑞:我在这儿.
Jerry: I'm here.
迈克:听着,杰瑞,我真的想说,我很抱歉,让你和拉吉不得不继续做夜班,因为我在这儿.
Mike: Listen Jerry, I really wanted to say that I'm sorry that you and Raj have to go back to this graveyard shift just because I'm here.
杰瑞:嘿,我懂.我理解这规矩.
Jerry: Hey, I've been around.I understand that this is how it works.
迈克:什么规矩?
Mike: How what works?
杰瑞:哈哈!是的,很好!
Jerry: Ha ha ha ha!Yeah, right!
迈克:我意思是,我不想这样.嘿,尼克.
Mike: I mean, I won't have any part of this.Hey Nick.
经理:我马上来,迈克.只要一秒钟.
Manager: I'll be right with you Mike.One second right.Here we go Winnie.
走这边,温妮,是这个吗?
Now is this the one.
温妮:哦,我不记得是否是这个,还是旁边那个.
Winnie: Oh I can't remember if this is the one, or the one next to it.
经理:哦,那么你不如两个都要,
Manager: Oh.Well why don't you take both of them and let your arthritis
让你的关节炎自己来决定?
decide?
温妮:哦,我付不起.
Winnie: Oh I can't afford both of them.
经理:好吧,送给你.我知道这店的经理是个非常好的人.
Manager: It's alright.They're on the house.It's alright.I heard the store manager's a real nice guy.
温妮:谢谢你.
Winnie: Thank you.
经理:什么事?
Manager: So, what's up?
迈克:喔,你真是一个好人.
Mike: Wow.Well, you are a nice guy.
经理:你也听说了?
Manager: You heard too hu?
迈克:是的,你给我调班因为我是个白人,是吗?
Mike: Yeah.Look, you gave me that shift change because I'm white.Didn't you?
经理:迈克,你去过喔喔店了?
Manager: Mike, have you been dipping into the Wow Wow's?
迈克:你们不卖喔喔的了.
Mike: You don't sell Wow Wow's anymore.
经理:是的,你突然问这些到底为什么呢.我们还是去我的办公室谈吧,跟我来.
Manager: Yes and your sudden outburst is exactly why.We better have a little pow wow in my office.Come on.
迈克:可能是有点误会,
Mike: Look, maybe this was just a big misunderstanding.
我们还是忘了它吧.
Why don't we forget the whole thing?
经理:不,不,请让我说清楚,我不想让你告诉别人我有种族偏见.
Manager: No, no.Please, let me straighten this out.I don't want you going around telling people I'm prejudice.
迈克:哦,你刚才的意思是……
Mike: Ok, um, what did you mean when you said...
经理:等一下.你不是犹太人,对吧?开个玩笑.
Manager: Wait a minute.You're not Jewish, are you?I'm only kidding.
迈克:是的.你说我们要关心自己的意思是什么呢?
Mike: Right.What did you mean when you said about us taking care of our own?
经理:哦,不.我没有羞辱的意思,我不想让你难过.只是因为这个世界上有很多不同种类的人,你我碰巧属于同一种.
Manager: Ah no.I didn't mean it as an insult.I didn't want to upset you.It's just that there are so many different kinds of people in this world, and you and I happen to be the same kind.
迈克:白人.
Mike: White.
经理:是的.如果一个黑人坐在经理的位置上,那么他会照顾杰瑞.
Manager: Well, yeah.If there were a black man sitting in this manager's chair, then he'd be looking out for Jerry.
迈克:我不知道……
Mike: Well, I don't know...
经理:如果经理是伊朗人或印度人,反正是和拉吉一样的人,
Manager: Or if the manager were Iranian or Indian or whatever Raj is,
你认为他会不会特别照顾拉吉呢?
don't you think that he'd be looking to give him a break or two?
迈克:我真的不想这么认为.
Mike: Well I didn't really think about it like that.
经理:这就是规矩.
Manager: Yeah.Well, that's the way it works.
迈克:但是,这看起来并不合理.
Mike: But, that doesn't seem right.
经理:嗯,但这是现实的世界,你得接受.
Manager: Um.Welcome to the real world.
迈克:那你说拉吉眼珠快掉下来时,
Mike: So you mean to tell me that you weren't making fun of Raj when you
你是不是取笑他吗?
were talking about his dot falling off?
经理:当你模仿他的语调时,你是在取笑他吗?
Manager: Well were you making fun of him when you were imitating his accent?
迈克:不是,我是开开玩笑的.
Mike: No.I was just fooling around.
经理:我也是.
Manager: So was I.
迈克:我已经有点糊涂了.
Mike: Well then I'm a little confused.
经理:如果我是一个吹牛的人,我怎么会有六个,
Manager: You see, if I were the kind of man who bragged,
实际上是七个少数民族雇员,
I would point out my six, actually seven Minority Employer of The Year awards.
并因此得了奖,你看那些.
You see those.
迈克:我没话说了.
Mike: I had no idea.
经理:我让新来的白人小伙做白班,这会让我成为一名有偏见的人吗?
Manager: So I give the new white kid a break.Does that make me a bigot?
底线在于,我对待他们是否和你有不同?
The bottom line is, have I treated them any different from how I treat you?
迈克:我想没有.
Mike: I guess not.
经理:你和杰瑞,拉吉就此事谈过吗?
Manager: Have you talked to Jerry and Raj about this?
迈克:谈过.
Mike: Yeah.
经理:然后呢?
Manager: And?
迈克:然后杰瑞说这是规矩.
Mike: And Jerry says that's just the way it works.
经理:聪明的孩子.你看他们没有问题,
Manager: Smart boy.You see they have no problem, I have no problem,
我没有问题,你怎么可能有问题呢?
so how could you have a problem?
迈克:我没有,我没有.我想我有点糊涂了.
Mike: I don't, I don't.I guess I was just a little confused.
经理:你知道吗?你会是一个好的管理人才.
Manager: You know what?You would be good management material.
迈克:哦,太好了,晚餐呢?我饿了.
Mike: Oh great, what's for dinner?I'm starved.
麦琪:煎饼.
Maggie: Burritos.
迈克:我真觉得脂肪多了些.
Mike: You know, I really should watch my saturated fats.
杰森:嘿,迈克,
Jason: Hey Mike, shouldn't we finish that conversation we started before
我们还没有完成上次你上班之前的谈话呢?
you left for work?
迈克:关于什么?
Mike: About what?
麦琪:我们只确定这和女孩无关.嘿,杰森?
Maggie: Well we are fairly sure it wasn't about girls.Hey Jason?
杰森:非常确信.
Jason: More sure than I've been about anything in my life.
迈克:哦,
Mike: Look, it turned out to be nothing.
已经没事了.你们有没有因为自己说错了话,
I mean have you ever just opened up your mouth and made a complete fool
而让自己成了个傻瓜?
of yourself?
麦琪:嗯,杰森?
Maggie: Um, Jason?
杰森:迈克,你要说什么?你在和谁说呢?
Jason: So mike.What did you say?Who did you say it to?
迈克:看,我原来以为我工作上得到了特别的照顾,
Mike: See, I just thought that I was getting special treatment at work
是因为我是个白人.
because I'm white.
麦琪:怎么回事?
Maggie: Excuse me?
迈克:好吧.所以我去问了尼克,他是经理,他说他只是照顾自己的同类.我不应该对此激动,这就是世界上的规矩.再见.
Mike: Yeah.So I asked Nick about it.He's the Manager and he explained that he was just taking care of his own kind, and I shouldn't get excited about it.That's the way the world works.See you.
杰森:等等,等一下.世界的规矩是什么?
Jason: Wait wait wait a minute.How's the way the world works?
迈克:就是因为他是白人,我是白人,他让我做白班,并不是因为他有种族偏见.
Mike: Well just because he's white and I'm white and he gave me a break, doesn't mean he's prejudiced.
杰森:不是?
Jason: It doesn't?
麦琪:迈克,你认为种族偏见是什么?
Maggie: Mike, what do you think prejudice means?
迈克:你知道,妈妈.比如不让某些人进入你的学校.或者用喷火管向他们喷射.你知道,报纸上写的.
Mike: Well you know mum.Like not letting certain people into your schools.Or uh, spraying them down with fire hoses.You know, stuff you see on the news.
杰森:迈克,迈克,
Jason: Mike, Mike, prejudice means giving somebody special treatment,
偏见指给某些人特殊的待遇,任何特殊的待遇.
any special treatment.
迈克:我糊涂了.
Mike: Well then I am confused.
麦琪:你怎么会糊涂呢?
Maggie: How could you be confused?
我们什么时候给你这样的观念,
Where did we ever give you the idea that it was alright to be a little
有一点偏见是合理的呢?
bit prejudiced?
迈克:不,不,妈妈.不是这样.我是说尼克得了奖,他的所有其他雇员都是少数民族.
Mike: No, no, no mum.It's not like that at all.I mean Nick has got awards and all his other employees are minorities.
杰森:是的,但是你说你换了班是因为你是白人.
Jason: Yeah well, but you said you got this shift change because you were white.
迈克:是的.
Mike: Well yeah.
杰森:那么什么让你糊涂呢,迈克?
Jason: Well then what's the confusion Mike?
迈克:我现在真的糊涂了.
Mike: Now I'm really confused.
杰森:让我给你理理清楚,迈克,
Jason: Well then let me straighten it out for you then Mike.
你去找那个尼克,你说:我不接受任何特殊待遇,我想要回夜班,
You go to this guy Nick, and you say: I don't accept any special treatment,
好吗,麦琪?
I want my old shift back.Right Maggie?
麦琪:嗯,杰森,这事我们以后再说.
Maggie: Uh.Jason, you and I should talk about this later.
杰森:我们应该当着迈克面说,这和迈克有关.
Jason: We can talk about it in front of Mike.This is about Mike.Come on.
来,这很重要,麦琪.
It's important.Maggie.
麦琪:我不想让我的儿子凌晨三点被捆起来,打死.
Maggie: I don't want my son shot at three am, over a pack of gum.
杰森:麦琪!
Jason: Maggie!
麦琪:是你问我的.
Maggie: You asked.
杰森:那么他应该利用这家伙的种族偏见吗?
Jason: Well so what.He should take advantage of this guys prejudice?
麦琪:不是.
Maggie: No.
杰森:那么你说了什么呢?
Jason: Well then what are you saying?
迈克:他说拉吉应该在凌晨三点被人打死.
Mike: She's saying that Raj should get shot at three in the morning.
麦琪:我不是这个意思.
Maggie: I am not.
我反对任何人在白天或者夜晚的任何时候被人打死.
And I'm against anybody being shot at any hour of the day or night.
拉吉是什么人?
And who the hell is Raj?
杰森:麦琪,这有关公平待遇.
Jason: Maggie, this is about unfair treatment.
麦琪:你想让他凌晨三点工作,
Maggie: You want him working at three in the morning with a gun under
柜台下面放着把枪吗?
the counter?
杰森:不,当然不是,我说的不是这个.
Jason: No, of course I don't.That is not what I'm talking about.
麦琪:杰森,杰森,
Maggie: Jason, Jason, I hate prejudice.
我痛恨种族偏见.但是那样会真的让我的儿子去上夜班.
But what would it really change to send our son back to the graveyard...shift.
杰森:但那是错误的.
Jason: But this is wrong.
麦琪:你是对的.
Maggie: You're right.
杰森:是的.你还知道其他什么情况吗?
Jason: Yes I am.Yes.You know something else?So are you.
迈克:我现在总算清楚了.
Mike: Well that sure clears everything right up for me.
麦琪:我倒希望这和女孩有关.
Maggie: I wish this had been about girls.
(第二天下午)
(The Next Afternoon)
迈克:嘿,杰瑞.你的班结束了.来.
Mike: Hey Jerry.Your shift is over.Come on.Alright.
杰瑞:如果尼克问起来,告诉他我在清理饮料?
Jerry: If Nick asks, tell him I'm stacking the soft drinks alright?
迈克:好的.找给你一块一毛六.
Mike: Right.Your change is a buck sixteen.
顾客:我想他们只有抱着电视或者足球时才会跑得这么快.
Customer: I thought they only moved that fast when they were carrying
a TV or football.
迈克:有趣.
Mike: Funny.
经理:这怎么了?杰瑞,杰瑞!
Manager: What the hell is this?Jerry!Jerry!
迈克:啊,尼克,杰瑞刚走.
Mike: Ah Nick, Jerry just left.
经理:他走了?我让他去整理汽水,看他搞得乱七八糟.这个懒家伙……我要扣他的薪水.
Manager: He left?I ask him to stack the soda and look at the mess he makes.That lazy son of a...His salary is going to be docked for this.
迈克:哦,尼克,
Mike: Oh, oh that.Oh Nick, Jerry didn't do that.I did.
不是杰瑞干的.我要来打扫的,
See I was going to clean it up,
但是我想我太忙了,忘记了.
but I guess I just got busy and forgot.
经理:你搞成这样?
Manager: You did this?
迈克:是的.
Mike: Yeah.
经理:哦,多加小心,孩子?
Manager: Oh, well uh, try to be more careful would you son?
有人打开了它,这不是意外.
Somebody unscrewed this.This was no accident.Wait a minute.
等一下,你不是因为太忙而忘记的,对吗?
You didn't get too busy and forget.Did you?
迈克:看,你知道吗,
Mike: Look, do you know that you are prejudiced,
你这是种族偏见,或者只是自欺欺人?
or are you just kidding yourself?
经理:你这个粗鲁而又狡猾的家伙,你都知道了,那么你是在想证明什么吗?
Manager: You rude smart arse know it all.What are you trying to prove here?Hu?
迈克:我不想,我刚刚证明了.
Mike: I'm not trying.I just proved it.
经理:你这个白面包真得跟我学,
Manager: You white bread suburban punks really get to me.
总有一天你会知道应该怎么做.
Some day you'll figure out what the score is.
迈克:是的,我刚才就做了.
Mike: Yeah, well I just did.
经理:你知道这个现实世界,你有很多东西要学.
Manager: You know you've got a lot to learn about the real world.
迈克:是的,我不会向你学.我退出.
Mike: Yeah.Well I won't be learning it from you.I quit.
经理:你知道什么?你这个小糊涂蛋.
Manager: You know something?You are one confused little kid.
迈克:不再是了.
Mike: Not anymore.
杰森:嘿,麦琪.今天怎么样?
Jason: Hey Maggie.How was your day?
麦琪:哦,还行.
Maggie: Oh not so hot.
杰森:我也是.
Jason: Mine neither.
麦琪:哦,宝贝,我不打算……
Maggie: Oh honey I didn't mean...
杰森:我不想……
Jason: I don't want...
麦琪和杰森:说下去.
Maggie and Jason: Go ahead.
杰森:当我们不能彼此交流的时候,我们不如谈一下迈克?
Jason: How are we supposed to communicate with Mike when we can't communicate with each other?
麦琪:等一下.你认为我们不能交流吗?
Maggie: Wait a minute.You don't think that we communicate?
杰森:闭嘴,吻我.
Jason: Shut up and kiss me.
迈克:你们好……
Mike: Hi guys...
麦琪:迈克,在你开口之前,我只想让你知道你的父亲是对的,你应该去做夜班.我不喜欢,但那是对的.
Maggie: Mike, before you say another word, I just want you to know that your father was right.You should go back on graveyard.I don't like it, but it's right.
迈克:我明白……
Mike: Well see, I...
杰森:等一下,我不对,麦琪.我不想让迈克有危险.
Jason: Wait a minute.I was not right Maggie.I don't want Mike endangering himself.
迈克:爸爸,不用担心.
Mike: Dad, don't worry.
杰森:我不得不担心.你是我儿子.
Jason: I have to worry.You're my son.
迈克:我退出了.
Mike: I quit.
麦琪:迈克,不管如何,你不能不做我们的儿子.
Maggie: Mike, no matter how old you get, you cannot quit being our son.
迈克:我不想退出我们这个家.我只是退出我的工作.
Mike: I don't mean I quit our family.I mean I quit our job.
我真的想谢谢你们两个,告诉我什么是对的.
And uh, I really want to thank you two for showing me what's right.
开萝尔,那讨厌的招聘广告在哪呢?
And Carol, where are the stinking wanted ads?
麦琪:杰森,他认为我们告诉他什么是对的.
Maggie: Jason, he thinks that we showed him what was right.
杰森:如果你不想的话我不会告诉他.00:21:18,200
Jason: I won't tell him if you don't.